# ALBERT AUGUSTINE



# PERSONAL SUMMARY

Software Developer with 4.3 years of experience building web applications. Extensive experience with Drupal and Laravel:

Drupal Developer - 4 years creating, customizing, and maintaining Drupal sites. Deep expertise in theming, module development, and site management.

Laravel Developer- 3 months experience rapidly developing applications using Laravel and implementing custom features and integrations.

## **SKILLS**

# Languages

- PHP
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery

#### **Frameworks**

- Drupal (8, 9, 10, 11)
- Laravel (MVC)

#### **Version Control**

• Git

#### **Tools & Platforms**

- Drush Commands
- Pantheon Platform
- Hostinger Platform
- Jira (Agile project management and issue tracking)
- Gulp
- NPM
- DDEV
- Docker
- Azure Blob Configuration
- Azure Storage Service Mounting

# Web Development Skills

- Upgraded multiple Drupal 9 sites to Drupal 10
- Working knowledge of LAMP stack
- Bootstrap Theming
- Bootstrap Table
- Experience with various HOOKs
- Working knowledge of Drupal AJAX and API calls
- Experience with REST APIs
- Experience with FCM (Firebase Cloud Messaging) push notifications
- Knowledge of Azure Deployment

## **CSS Preprocessors**

- SASS
- LESS

#### **Responsive Design**

Experience with media queries

#### **Automation**

 Automating Sass compilation using Gulp and NPM

# **EXPERIENCE**

## **Appstation Pvt Ltd**

Drupal developer | Trivandrum, India |

September 2024 – Current

#### NDimensionZ Solutions Pvt Ltd

Drupal developer | Kochi, India |

October 2023 - May 2024

#### POWER CMS TECHNOLOGY

Drupal developer | Trivandrum, India |

February 2021 - September 2023

## **PROJECTS**

#### NDZ Canada - Build in Drupal 9

Project NDZ Canada is a branch site of NDimensionZ Solutions Pvt Ltd. The site is a replica of the original site but built in Drupal 9 with a different theme.

#### Supplyco ERPDASHBOARD

Project develop an admin dashboard to manage and Monitor an organization's ERP system. Centralize operations, track KPI's and visualize metrics through charts and reports Enable data - driven decision making to optimize ERP performance.

#### Nine4seven - Build in Drupal 9

Nine4seven is a Drupal-based software project. This project is MEP (Mechanical, Electrical and Plumbing) based service company. The site mainly shows their services, projects, and designs.

# Financial Experts Network-Build in Drupal 8, Drupal 9

Financial Experts Network provides finance webinars live and on-demand. Experts host live webinars on personal finance topics. Recordings are stored for replay access. Enables continuous learning via webinar videos and materials. Open to finance professionals and individual investors.

#### Big Fund Raising Ideas - Build in Drupal 9

This project is an e-commerce website that allows users to browse and purchase products online.

#### Enable Ireland - Build in Drupal 9

Enable Ireland is a site that provides services to children and adults with disabilities and their families from over 40 locations in 15 counties. Covering childhood to adulthood our expert teams work with the individual and their family on a plan for each life Stage.

#### Ipbes - Build in Drupal 9, Drupal 10

Ipbes is a Drupal-based software project. This project is to protect extinct animals. The site mainly shows the services, seminar through zoom (zoomapi), and published blogs etc.

### MCIT-Safespace - Build in Drupal 10

Upgraded the site from Drupal 8 to Drupal 10, ensuring compatibility and enhanced performance. Implemented Azure Redis for improved caching and site responsiveness.

#### MCIT-Ilab- Build in Drupal 10

Upgraded the site from Drupal 8 to Drupal 10, ensuring compatibility and enhanced performance. Fixed security related issues.

## MCIT-Coders-Build in Drupal 10

Upgraded the site from Drupal 8 to Drupal 10, ensuring compatibility and enhanced performance. Fixed security related issues.

## Designbathae-Build in Drupal 10

Designbathae is a theme-based project built on Drupal 10, featuring comprehensive theming and backend development. The project includes a custom theme designed to meet client specifications, with various features implemented to enhance user experience. Server hosting is managed using Hostinger.

# Qatar Museum - Build in Drupal 11

Developed a middleware solution using Drupal 11 to connect a Flutter application with a CRM system. Implemented push notifications through the Drupal admin portal and REST API for real-time user engagement. Managed CRM API integration, providing a consolidated API for seamless data access in the Flutter app.

# **CONTRIBUTION**

#### **API Data Connector**

- Provides a dynamic autocomplete feature for fields in Drupal.
- Fetches data from an external API.
- Enhances user experience by allowing quick search and selection.
- Simplifies integration of external data sources into forms.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- DRUPAL 10 & 9 TUTORIAL -Drupal Master Class, Udemy on Oct 2023 Oct 2023.
- OOP Object Oriented Programming In PHP 7, Udemy on Nov 2024 Nov 2024.

# **EDUCATION**

- B.Tech Electrical and Electronics
- Higher Secondary Board of Higher Secondary Examinations, Kerala